http://www.powerbasic.com/privacy-notice

Register
Log in
Shopping cart
(0)
You have no items in your shopping cart.
Privacy Policy
This website and other related websites and mobile applications (collectively referred to as the "Sites") comprise various web pages and services operated by PowerBasic Tools, LLC ("PowerBASIC", "we", "us" or "our").
We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal information as described in this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy"). We use the information we collect about you through your use of the Sites and that you provide to us to process orders and to provide a more personalized Internet experience. This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect on the PowerBASIC Sites and through email, text or other electronic communications between you and the Sites. It does not apply to information collected by us offline or by other means, including by any other website operated by Drake Enterprises, Ltd. (including our affiliates and subsidiaries) or any third party, including any application or content that may link to or be accessible from or on the Sites.
Please read on for more details about our Privacy Policy.
The Sites are not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.
What information do we collect? How do we use it?
We collect information that you provide to us directly and we only use your personal data when the law allows us to. We use your personal information for the purposes for which we collected it. Most commonly, we collect your data to provide you services and software products through our Sites. For example, when you place an order through our online store, we will need to know basic identification and payment method information - name, email address, mailing address, phone number, credit card number/expiration, PayPal account, etc. This information allows us to fulfill our contract with you, process your order and notify you of your order status. When you opt-in and sign up for the Electronic Gazette and new product notices, we need only an email address, which we use to send the information you requested.
We personalize your shopping experience by using your purchases to shape our recommendations about the books, add-ons, and other merchandise that might be of interest to you. As you browse and interact with our Sites, we automatically collect technical data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage to help us develop the design and layout of the Sites. We may also use the information we collect to occasionally notify you about important functionality changes to the Sites, new PowerBASIC services, and special offers we think you'll find valuable.
We also collect, use and disclose non-personal, aggregated data for any purpose. If aggregated data can be combined with or connected to your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat that combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
What are the legal bases for our collection of your information?
We collect your data to provide our services to you and to fulfill any contract we enter into with you, such as the sale of our products or services.
Also, we collect your data out of a legitimate business interest to the extent that our business interest is not overridden by your applicable rights or interests.
We also collect your data with your express consent. By clicking the "I Accept" button when first using our Sites, setting up an account with us, and/or purchasing any of our products or services, you are expressly and freely consenting to allow PowerBASIC to collect and process your data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us at support@powerbasic.com. However, if we still have the need to collect and/or process your data due to an existing contract with us or out of another legitimate and overriding business interest, we will continue to process your data to the limited extent allowed by applicable law.
Will PowerBASIC disclose the information it collects to outside parties?
PowerBASIC does not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to third parties. We may offer advertising space to third parties on our Sites, but no personal information is shared with any third party without asking you first and getting your consent. If you do not choose to contact third party advertisers, they will not have any information about you. We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party for marketing purposes. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing messages from PowerBASIC at any time by contacting us.
We may disclose your personal information to comply with a valid subpoena, court order, governmental request or other legal obligation.
What about "cookies"?
"Cookies" are small files of information that are stored by your browser on your computer. When you first visit our Site, you will receive a notice informing you that cookies are used by PowerBASIC in providing the Sites and services. By clicking OK and continuing to browse the Sites, you signify that you understand and agree to our use of cookies.
You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the appropriate settings on your browser to refuse or restrict cookies, and you may delete cookies after they have been placed on your computer or device at any time. If you refuse or restrict cookies on your browser, some parts of the Sites may not function properly.
Data Transfers and Processing
PowerBASIC is headquartered in Franklin, North Carolina in the United States. Our Sites are hosted and administrated in the United States or hosted with cloud service providers who are headquartered in the United States. If you are located in the European Economic Area ("EEA"), or anywhere outside of the United States, be aware that information you provide to us or that we obtain as a result of your use of our Sites and services will be processed in, transferred to, and stored in the United States. The privacy and data protection laws of the United States may be different from the laws of your country of residence and may not protect your personal data to the same level as laws of the EEA or give you the same rights that you have in the EEA. Transfer of your data from PowerBASIC to its parent and/or sister companies will be done in accordance with this Privacy Policy. These data transfers are necessary to provide our services and to globally operate and provide our services and products to you. By clicking the "I Accept" button when setting up an account and/or purchasing any of our goods or services, you also provide your consent to these data transfers.
Data Security
We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorized way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.
How long will you use my personal data for?
We only retain your personal data for as long as reasonably necessary to fulfill the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or reporting requirements. We may retain your personal data for a longer period in the event of a complaint or if we reasonably believe there is a prospect of litigation with respect to our relationship with you.
To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and applicable legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or other requirements.
Your Consent
By using our Sites and clicking "Accept" on the initial cookies notification you receive, you consent to the collection and use of your information by PowerBASIC consistent with this Privacy Policy. In the process of creating an account and/or purchasing any of PowerBASIC's products or services, you will be given an opportunity to accept or reject additional collection and processing of your data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Some collection or processing of your data is necessary for us to enter into a contract with you, and or for other legitimate business interests. In order to receive e-mail reminders and other marketing communications from PowerBASIC unrelated to your orders, you must opt-in to receive communications from us. You can ask us to stop sending you marketing communications at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or by contacting us. Where you opt-out of marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of products purchased by you through our Sites or other transactions. If you choose to opt-out of receiving marketing communications, we will not send you messages about new products and services.
Your Legal Rights
Based on your country of residence or if you are located in the EEA, you may have rights under certain data protection laws in relation to your personal data, including the right to request access to your personal data, request a correction to your personal data, request erasure of your personal data, object to processing your personal data, including to object to direct marketing, request restriction of processing your personal data, request the transfer of your personal data and the right to withdraw consent related to use of your personal data. If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us at support@powerbasic.com. We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This security measure ensures that personal information is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may contact you to ask you for additional information related to your request to assist our response. We try to respond to all legitimate requests as soon as possible and in any event within one month. Occasionally, it could take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made multiple requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
Links to Third Party Websites
The Sites may contain links to other websites, plug-ins and applications ("Linked Sites"). Clicking on Linked Sites may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. PowerBASIC does not control these Linked Sites and we are not responsible for the privacy practices of any Linked Sites. When you leave the Sites, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of each website you visit.
Changes to this Privacy Policy and Correcting Your Information
We regularly review our Privacy Policy terms and conditions and may update this Privacy Policy by notifying you of any material changes through our Sites or through the contact information you provide to us. You are responsible for maintaining the accuracy of information you provide to us, such as your contact and billing information. Please notify us of any changes to your information by emailing support@powerbasic.com.
Questions about this Privacy Policy
If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, please contact us at:
Copyright © 2020 PowerBASIC Tools, LLC. All rights reserved.
